ABBY AUTIN, SSM

New Orleans, LA **↑** 504.909.9808 ****

abby.autin@gmail.com ■

abbynautin in

AbbyAutin.com #



OVERVIEW

Certified SAFe Scrum Master. Computer Science undergrad. Seasoned Revenue & Sales Director with over 10 years' experience managing multi-property and multi-market hotel groups. Specialized in revenue management, sales strategy, and B2B SaaS training & configuration.



EDUCATION

Computer Science | University of New Orleans

JAN 2018 - DEC 2021

3.79 GPA. Completed Software Development I & II, Machine Structure & Assembly Language, and Data Structures.

Accounting | University of New Orleans

AUG 2014 - DEC 2017

3.9 GPA. Completed Principles of Accounting, Intermediate Accounting, Accounting Information Systems, Management & Organization Behavior, and Statistics.



EXPERIENCE

Director of Revenue & Sales | French Quarter Hotel Collection

AUG 2011 - DEC 2014

Managing a centralized revenue & sales department for a hotel collection spanning the New Orleans and Bahamas markets. Responsible for capturing incremental revenue through custom room categories and rate packages, developing & implementing inventory and pricing strategies, developing marketing campaigns, forecasting future demand & pricing trends, and creating annual budgets with management team.

Revenue Manager | New Orleans Hotel Consultants

DEC 2007 - AUG 2011

Directing a centralized reservations department for a group of six hotels across the New Orleans, Mexico, and Natchez markets. Responsible for developing inventory & pricing strategies to maximize revenue, managing room rates & inventory across several distribution channels, working with sales team on room rate contracts and terms, securing rate contracts with OTA partners, developing marketing campaigns with Director of Sales, managing a reservations team of 5, creating revenue projections, tracking and analyzing consumer trends, overseeing PMS conversions, configuring SaaS property management systems, and working on annual budgets with CFO.



- Strategic problem solver
- Team player
- Outgoing
- Leader

- Insatiably curious
- Analytical
- Driven
- Loves challenges

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded the Francine Foreman Women in STEM Scholarship. University of New Orleans, Fall 2019
- During my tenure, increased hotel ADR (Average Daily Rate) by 30% through reconfiguring existing room types, increasing overall value. French Quarter Hotel Collection
- As part of a New Orleans management team, flew to the Bahamas to consult hotel staff on operations and management in preparation for hotel grand opening. Configured SaaS property management system (PMS) and trained staff on new program. -The Cove Resort Eleuthera Bahamas, March 2013
- Oversaw SaaS PMS conversion & configured new PMS, Web Rez Pro. Trained all hotel staff on the new program during the transition from Country Inn & Suites to the Natchez Grand Hotel. -Natchez Grand Hotel, June 2009
- Configured SaaS PMS, Web Rez Pro, and trained all hotel staff on new program during hotel acquisition. -Hotel Aventura Mexicana, Playa del Carmen, Aug 2007
- Oversaw SaaS PMS conversion & configured new web-based PMS, Web Rez Pro. -Ambassador Hotel New Orleans, Jan 2007

VOLUNTEERING

Data Structures Note-Taker | Disability Services – University of New Orleans JUN 2019 – AUG 2019

For one of my classmates, took detailed notes and diagrams from in-class lectures, interpreted the information, and typed up thorough and articulate explanations of concepts, ideas, and data structures as presented by the professor. Notes had to be readable via the VoiceOver utility.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified SAFe Scrum Master | Scaled Agile Inc.

ISSUED: DEC 2019